Guide to the Max Wilk Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Max Wilk papers
1735-2011
1944-2005
YCAL MSS 828
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
114.32
(167 boxes) + 2 record album storage.
The collection consists of typescript drafts of books, plays, screenplays, radio plays, teleplays, and notes, transcripts of interviews, and other research materials relating to Wilk's various writing projects; correspondence with friends, professional colleagues, and research subjects; scrapbooks; audiovisual material; printed material including magazines, books, and stage production programs of shows he wrote or attended; posters; music scores; and other materials documenting Wilk's literary and show business career.
Wilk, Max, 1920-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired primarily through purchase and gift from Max Wilk, 1944-2011. For more information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 47-49, 90, 107-117, 135, 139, 148, 149, 163-163 (audiovisual materials): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 92, 118, 167 (record album storage): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 91, 136, 169 (electronic files): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Max Wilk (1920-2011)
Max Wilk graduated from Yale University in 1941, where he studied drama and was active in the Yale Dramatic Association. He was the author of numerous articles, books, stage, radio, and television plays, and filmscripts. His works for the stage include the comedy Cloud 7 (1958) and the book for A Musical Jubilee (1975), both of which had Broadway runs. He adapted his short story, "It Happened to Jane" for the film starring Doris Day and Jack Lemmon in 1959, and his novel Don't Raise the Bridge, Lower the River for the film with Jerry Lewis in 1968. Wilk is also the author of Every Day's a Matinee: Memoirs Scribbled on a Dressing Room Door (1975), The Golden Age of Television: Notes from the Survivors (1976), OK! The Story of Oklahoma! (2002), Schmucks with Underwoods: Conversations with Hollywood's Classic Screenwriters (2004), and They're Playing Our Song: Conversations With America's Classic Songwriters. He died in Westport, Connecticut in 2011.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of typescript drafts of books, plays, screenplays, radio plays, teleplays, and notes, transcripts of interviews, and other research materials relating to Wilk's various writing projects; correspondence with friends, professional colleagues, and research subjects; scrapbooks; audiovisual material; printed material including magazines, books, and stage production programs of shows he wrote or attended; posters; music scores; and other materials documenting Wilk's literary and show business career.
Arrangement
Organized into forty groupings: I. Early Acquisitions. II. November 1984 Acquisition. III. February 1986 Acquisition. IV. April 1988 Acquisition. V. December 1988 Acquisition. VI. February 1989 Acquisition. VII. October 1989 Acquisition. VIII. November 1990 Acquisition. IX. January 1991 Acquisition. X. September 1991 Acquisition. XI. November 1992 Acquisition. XII. December 1992 Acquisition. XIII. April 1993 Acquisition. XIV. December 1993 Acquisition. XV. October 1995 Acquisition. XVI. January 1996 Acquisition. XVII. October 1996 Acquisition. XVIII. November 1997 Acquisition. XIX. May 1998 Acquisition. XX. November 1998 Acquisition. XXI. January 1999 Acquisition. XXII. October 1999 Acquisition. XXIII. December 1999 Acquisition. XXIV. May 2000 Acquisition. XXV. May 2001 Acquisition. XXVI. October 2001 Acquisition. XXVII. November 2001 Acquisition. XXVIII. April 2002 Acquisition. XXIX. October 2002 Acquisition. XXX. November 2002 Acquisition. XXXI. November 2002 Acquisition. XXXII. January 2003 Acquisition. XXXIII. February 2003 Acquisition. XXXIV. May 2003 Acquisition. XXXV. May 2004 Acquisition. XXXVI. 2008 Acquisitions. XXXVII. February 2009 Acquisition. XXXVIII. August 2011 Acquisition. XXXIX. October 2016 Acquisition. XXXX. September 2017 Acquisition.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with and/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
American drama -- 20th Century; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Dramatists, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Screenwriters -- United States; Television writers -- United States; Audiovisual materials; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Scripts -- United States -- 20th Century; Sound recordings -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; Screenwriters -- United States -- 20th Century; Television writers -- United States -- 20th Century; Wilk, Max, 1920-
- Early Acquisitions, 1947-1982; 1; 3.08; (4 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes typescript novels, screenplays, and stage and television scripts by Wilk and others, with letters to Wilk from Walter Prichard Eaton and other papers.
  - Manuscripts: A - Z
    - "The Beard", undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - "Blind Hate", undated (Box 1)
    - "Close-up", 1947; 3 (Box 1)
    - "Don't Raise the Bridge (Lower the River)", 1963-1969; 6 (Box 1)
    - "Home on the Range", undated (Box 1)
    - "One of Our Brains.. .", 1965-1968; 2 (Box 1)
    - "Open Secret", 1947; 2 (Box 1)
    - "Small Wonder", 1955 (Box 1)
    - "That's Our Sherman", 1948 May 3 (Box 1)
    - "Three Cheers.. .", undated (Box 1)
    - "We Called It Music", undated (Box 1)
    - "Who Listens?", undated (Box 1)
  - Television Scripts: A - Z
    - "Ammident", circa 1950 (Box 2)
    - Barry, Jack, Show, 1951 (Box 2)
    - "XXXXX Isn't Everything TV", 1954 (Box 2)
    - Big Town TV: Wilk, 1950-1951; 2 (Box 2)
    - Borge, Victor, Show, 1951; 2 (Box 2)
    - CBS TV: Kimbrough, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Coca, Imogene, Show: Script 1, undated (Box 2)
    - Coca, Imogene, Show: Script 2, 1954 October 16 (Box 2)
    - Coca, Imogene, Show: Script 2A, 1954 October 9 (Box 2)
    - Janet Dean TV, 1953, undated; 2 (Box 2)
    - Emerson, Faye, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Elser, 1949 December 30 (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Ferber, undated (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Hart, undated (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Job, 1950 (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Kesselring, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Lindsay, 1949 (Box 2)
    - Ford TV: Scott, 1948 (Box 2)
    - Hayes, Peter Lind, Show, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Karloff, Boris: Axelrod, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Karloff, Boris: Obler, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Karloff, Boris: Wilk, 1949 (Box 3)
    - Nash Airflyte: Christie, undated (Box 3)
    - Nash Airflyte: Glaspell, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Nash Airflyte: Merrick, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Nash Airflyte: Milne, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Philco TV: Rogow, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Philco TV: Shapiro, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Philco TV: Wilk, 1951; 2 (Box 3)
    - Rodgers, Richard, Show, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Shay, Dorothy, Show, undated (Box 3)
    - Starlight Theatre, 1950 (Box 3)
    - Wynn, Ed, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Eaton, Walter Prichard, 1933-1944 (Box 3)
  - "The Waterbury Tales", undated (Box 3)
  - "Too Many Boys", undated (Box 3)
  - Film Report: C-435 - Air - Sea Rescue, 1944 August 22 (Box 3)
  - "Maul it Over", 1944 May 23 (Box 3)
  - Envelopes addressed to Max Wilk, 1982, undated (Box 3)
  - The Yank: The Army Weekly, v.4 no. 5, 1945 July 20 (Box 4 (Oversize))
- November 1984 Acquisition, 1937-1984; 2; 0.21; (1 box)
  Typescript, stage production programs, and other material.
  - "The Waterbury Tales," typescript, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - The Waterbury Tales, Yale Dramatic Association, stage production program, 1941 (Box 5)
  - The Tragical History of Doctor Faustus stage production program; Letter to Orson Welles; and audience survey questionaire, 1937-1941, 1984 (Box 5)
- 1986 Acquisitions, 1941-1986; 3; 1.5; (4 boxes)
  Typescripts and proofs for writings by Wilk, and screenplay by Daniel Totheroth.
  - "And Did You Once See Sidney Plain?," proofs, 1986; 2 (Box 6)
  - "They're Playing Our Song," typescripts, 1973; 4 (Box 6)
  - "A Tough Act to Follow," typescripts, 1985; 6 (Box 6)
  - "A Tough Act to Follow," proofs, 1985; 3 (Box 6)
  - "The Wit and Wisdom of Hollywood," typescripts, 1971; 2 (Box 6)
  - "The Wit and Wisdom of Hollywood," typescripts, 1971; 4 (Box 7)
  - "And Did You Once See Sidney Plain?" proofs, 1986 (Box 8 (Oversize))
  - "A Certain Mr. Scratch," typed screenplay, mimeograph copy, based on the story "The Devil and Daniel Webster" by Stephen Vincent Benét., 1941 (Box 138)
- April 1988 Acquisition, 1951-1986; 4; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Typescripts, proofs, paste-up, and reproductions of drawings by Al Hirschfield, for a book and screenplay by Wilk.
  - "And Did You Once See Sidney Plain?," galley, page proofs and a paste-up, 1986; 3 (Box 9)
  - "Don't Raise the Bridge, Lower the River," shooting script and typescript, undated (Box 9)
  - "The Fast Dollar," typescript, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Hirschfeld, A. "And Did You Once See Sidney Plain?" photostats and repros of illustrations, 1951-1986 (Box 10 (Oversize))
- December 1988 Acquisition, 1902-1993; 5; 1; (1 box)
  Typescripts and publications by Wilk and others.
  - Manuscripts
    - "American Treasure Hunt," 2nd copy, [1985?]; 2 (Box 11)
    - "The Man that Corrupted Hadleyburg", circa 1977 (Box 11)
    - "The Mighty Ten-Inch Screen" photocopy, undated; 2 (Box 11)
  - Publications
    - Penguin Parade 4, undated (Box 11)
    - The Stephen Vincent Benet Pocket Book, 1938 (Box 11)
    - College Joker, 1906 (Box 11)
    - Drummers' Samples, 1902 (Box 11)
    - Ogilvie's Slow Train and What Happened on it, 1908 (Box 11)
    - Oh, You Auto See the United States With Jackson, 1957 (Box 11)
    - On a Slow Train Through Arkansas, 1903 (Box 11)
    - On a Slow Train: The Original Story, 1904 (Box 11)
    - On the Hog Train Through Kansas, 1906 (Box 11)
    - Thomas W. Jackson: Coming With Good Stuff, undated (Box 11)
    - Variety Joker no.2, 1909 (Box 11)
    - OK! The Story of Oklahoma, 1993 (Box 11)
    - 365 Days, 1936 (Box 11)
- February 1989 Acquisition, 1906-1908; 6; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  Scrapbook and vocal score.
  - Scrapbook of clippings related to theatre, 1906, undated (Box 12 (Oversize))
  - "Get on the Raft with Taft," score by Harry D. Kerr and Abe Holzman, 1908 (Box 13 (Oversize))
- October 1989 Acquisition, 1920-1978; 7; 0.21; (1 box)
  Vocal scores and program from the show Small Wonder and miscellaneous publications.
  - Small Wonder stage production program, 1948 (Box 14)
  - "Show Off," vocal score, 1948 (Box 14)
  - "When I Fall In Love," vocal score, 1948 (Box 14)
  - Evergreen Review, v.3 no.9, 1959 (Box 14)
  - These Women!, 1978 (Box 14)
  - The Veil of Happiness, 1920 (Box 14)
- November 1990 Acquisition, 1935-1963; 8; 1.83; (3 boxes)
  "The Waterbury Tales," typescript, theater programs, and other printed material.
  - "The Waterbury Tales," typescript, undated (Box 15)
  - One Hundred Years of Famous Pages From The New York Times: 1851-1951 (Box 15)
  - Theatre production programs
    - Shubert Theatre, New Haven, 1937-1963; 3 (Box 15)
    - Yale Dramatic Association, New Haven, 1941-1952 (Box 15)
    - New York theatres, 1935-1942; 11 (Box 15)
    - New York theatres, 1942-1946; 7 (Box 16)
    - New York theatres, 1946-1958; 5 (Box 17)
- January 1991 Acquisition, undated; 9; 0.08; (1 box)
  - Piano-conductor score for The Girls Against the Boys, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
- September 1991 Acquisition, 1945-1983; 10; 1; (1 box)
  Material relating to Wilk's research on Hallie Flanagan and the Federal Theater Project; a radio script; and a group of theater production programs.
  - "Hallie Flanagan," television scripts, 1975-1983; 3 (Box 19)
  - "Hallie Flanagan," oral history transcripts, 1975-1983; 3 (Box 19)
  - "The Bishop Misbehaves," radio script, 1952 (Box 19)
  - Stage production programs, 1945-1964, undated; 11 (Box 19)
- November 1992 Acquisition, 1944-1963; 11; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Theater production programs from Boston, New York, New Haven and other cities.
  - New Haven and Connecticut stage production programs, 1945-1963; 4 (Box 20)
  - Boston, New York and other stage production programs, 1944-1959; 2 (Box 20)
  - Boston, New York and other stage production programs, 1947-1963; 2 (Box 21)
- December 1992 Acquisition, 1934-1955; 12; 0.21; (1 box)
  Correspondence between Erle Stanley Gardner and Jacob Wilk and Max Wilk, and between Max Wilk and Ober Ridgefield and Mrs. Georges Simenon.
  - Correspondence
    - Gardner, Erle Stanley to Jacob Wilk, 1951, 1955; 2 (Box 22)
    - Gardner, Erle Stanley to Max Wilk, 1934 June 27 (Box 22)
    - Gardner, Erle Stanley to Jacob and Max Wilk, 1954 (Box 22)
    - Wilk, Max to Mr. Ober Ridgefield, 1954 November 18 (Box 22)
    - Simenon, Mrs Georges to Max Wilk, 1954-1955 (Box 22)
- April 1993 Acquisition, 1990; 13; 0.25; (2 boxes)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 49 contains audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Contact Access Services for further information.
  - Press release and clippings related to OK! The Story of Oklahoma!, [1993] (Box 23)
    Related Materials
    There is an audiocassette related to this material that can be found in Box 23.
  - "Memo from Max Wilk 'Oklahoma!'", 1990; 1 (Box 49, Item barcode 39002109974395)
    Use of original audiocassette is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    This audiocassette is related to material that can be found in Box 23.
- December 1993 Acquisition, 1929-1993; 14; 0.25; (1 box)
  - Scrapbook of Alan Crosland containing clippings related to the motion picture industry, 1929-1930 (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - Stage production programs from New Haven, New York, Boston, and other theaters, 1931-1961 (Box 24 (Oversize))
  - "Celebrating 50 Years in 1993, Rogers and Hammerstein," gift bag (Box 24 (Oversize))
- October 1995 Acquisition, 1940-1975; 15; 0.79; (4 boxes)
  Note from Stephen Vincent Benet with printed poem by Benet; production files, proofs, and illustrations for OK! The Story of Oklahoma! by Wilk; and piano-conductor score for Irene.
  - Letter to Max Wilk from Stephen Vincent Benet; and printed poem Nightmare at Noon by Benet, 1940, undated (Box 25)
  - "Oklahoma! The Story of Oklahoma!" illustrations, undated; 2 (Box 25)
  - "Oklahoma! The Story of Oklahoma!" production files and proofs, undated; 4 (Box 26 (Oversize))
  - "Oklahoma! The Story of Oklahoma!" production files and proofs, undated; 2 (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Mailers, undated (Box 27 (Oversize))
  - Irene piano-conductor score inscribed to Albert Seldon from Mathilde Pincus and Al Miller, 1975 May 20 (Box 28 (Oversize))
- January 1996 Acquisition, 1955-1967; 16; 0.21; (1 box)
  Typescript television scripts and screenplays, and television show outline.
  - "Ask Me No Questions," television script, 1956, undated; 2 (Box 29)
  - "Don't Raise the Bridge, Lower the River," screenplay, 1967 April (Box 29)
  - "In the Last Analysis," outline for television comedy, 1955 December 2 (Box 29)
  - "Mad Money," television script, undated (Box 29)
  - "Melina Mercouri's Greece," television script, 1965 (Box 29)
- October 1996 Acquisition, 1945-1982; 17; 0.21; (1 box)
  Writings and printed material by or relating to Max Wilk, and untitled manuscripts by Gene Fowler.
  - "Cloud Seven," playscript, 1958 (Box 30)
  - "Hello Mom," radio scripts, 1945 April 28 (Box 30)
  - "Hello Mom," radio script, 1945 May 19 (Box 30)
  - "Hello Mom," radio script, 1945 June 2 (Box 30)
  - "Wings Over the Nation," radio script, 1945 May 26 (Box 30)
  - "Wings Over the Nation," radio script, 1945 April 26 (Box 30)
  - "Western Sketch, Small Wonder, Duchess Dafour", 1948 (Box 30)
  - "People vs. Holt, McBride: Co. et al", undated (Box 30)
  - Fowler, Gene, manuscripts, undated (Box 30)
  - American Film, 1982 (Box 30)
  - Untitled script, undated (Box 30)
- November 1997 Acquisition, 1980-1981; 18; 0.21; (1 box)
  Correspondence concerning the Armed Forces Editions paperback book publications.
  - Correspondence from E. B. White, Erskine Caldwell, Leo Rosten, Margaret Farrar, and Publishers Weekly, 1980-1981 (Box 31)
- May 1998 Acquisition, 1962-1963; 19; 0.21; (1 box)
  - "Museum of Modern Art Presents Television USA: 13 Seasons," poster; list of New Dramatists, typescript (photocopy); Clipping of article by Wilk from Variety (photocopy), 1962-1963, undated (Box 32)
- November 1998 Acquisition, 1959-1981; 20; 0.21; (1 box)
  Typescripts of screenplays and works relating to S. J. Perelman and Donald Ogden Stewart by Wilk.
  - "The Man That Corrupted Hadleyburg," screenplay, 1977 October (Box 33)
  - "My Masterpiece," screenplay, 1978 July (Box 33)
  - Perelman, Stewart, 1959-1981 (Box 33)
- January 1999 Acquisition, 1951-1982; 21; 0.21; (1 box)
  - New Dramatists address list, undated (Box 34)
  - Letter from Fred Coe to Max Wilk, 1951 September 14 (Box 34)
  - Printed material, 1962-1982; 2 (Box 34)
    "Recollections of Fitzgerald and Hemingway," by Donald Ogden Stewart, inscribed to Max [Wilk] by D[onald] O[gden] S[tewart].
- October 1999 Acquisition, 1974-1990; 22; 0.21; (1 box)
  Typescripts of writings by Wilk.
  - "Noodles," typescript of novel, 1974 (Box 35)
  - "Catlin and the Indians," a four-part mini-series for television, 1983 January (Box 35)
  - "Overture and Finale" [about Rodgers and Hammerstein], 1990 (Box 35)
- December 1999 Acquisition, 1958-1974; 23; 0.21; (1 box)
  Production programs.
  - Leland Hayward presents: "Year-end review" program, 1958 (Box 36)
  - "The Trial of the Catonsville Nine" program, 1971 (Box 36)
  - "Presenting Leland Hayward," program, 1974 September 18 (Box 36)
- May 2000 Acquisition, undated; 24; 0.21; (1 box)
  Book proposal and typescript for "Broadway's Fabulous Fifites: In the Words of the Artists Who Made Them Happen" with typed transcripts of New Dramatists Craft Discussions.
  - "Broadway's Fabulous Fifties: In the Words of the Artists Who Made Them Happen," book proposal, typescript, undated (Box 37)
  - "A New Dramatists Craft Discussion with Arthur Miller," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
  - "A New Dramatists Craft Discussion with Mary Drayton," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
  - "A New Dramatists Craft Discussion with Paddy Chayefsky and Howard Lindsay," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
  - "A New Dramatists Craft Discussion with Abe Burrows, Russel Crouse, and Howard Lindsay," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
  - "A New Dramatists Craft Discussion with Elia Kazan," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
  - "A Talk on Playwriting by Howard Lindsay," transcript of a recording (photocopy), undated (Box 37)
- May 2001 Acquisition, [2000?]; 25; 0.21; (1 box)
  - "Voices of the Twentieth Century," compiled by Max Wilk, typescript, annotated (photocopy); with a schedule and an announcement of the reading at the Century Club, [2000?] (Box 38)
- October 2001 Acquisition, 1944-1954; 26; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Typescript and printed material.
  - "Storm Warning Redux," typescript (photocopy) of article by Max Wilk, undated (Box 39)
  - Memory Lane, 1890 to 1925, Ragtime, Jazz, Foxtrot and Other Popular Music and Music Covers, selected by Max Wilk, proofs of cover and illustrations, [1973] (Box 39)
  - Commedie Di Carlo Goldoni, 1844 (Box 39)
  - How Private George W. Peck Put Down the Rebellion, undated (Box 39)
  - Night Must Fall, 1935 (Box 39)
  - Red Treason on Broadway, 1954 (Box 39)
  - The Man Shakespeare and His Tragic Life Story, 1921 (Box 40)
- November 2001 Acquisition, 2000-2001; 27; 0.29; (2 boxes)
  Tyescripts, posters, and window cards.
  - "Voices of the 20th Century," compiled by Max Wilk, typescript, 2000 October (Box 41)
  - "You Should Have Been There," typescript, 2001 october (Box 41)
  - Cloud 7, Golden Theatre window card, undated (Box 42 (Oversize))
  - Yale Dramatic Association posters and window cards for Here We Go Again, Merton of the Movies, Too Many Boys and The Waterbury Tales, undated; 4 (Box 42 (Oversize))
- April 2002 Acquisition, 1967-2000; 28; 1; (1 box)
  Writings, correspondence, and printed material by or relating to Max Wilk.
  - "Irving Berlin", 1971-1972 (Box 43)
  - "Vernon Duke", 1971 (Box 43)
  - "Sammy Cahn", 1972 (Box 43)
  - "Margaret Whiting", undated (Box 43)
  - Out ms pages, "They're playing our song", 1970 (Box 43)
  - "Gershwin and outpages, TPOS", 1972, 1994 (Box 43)
  - "Arlen", undated (Box 43)
  - "Warren", undated (Box 43)
  - "Youmans, 1972 (Box 43)
  - "Sondheim", undated (Box 43)
  - "Ira Gershwin", 1971 (Box 43)
  - "Rogers - Kern - Hammerstein", 1971 (Box 43)
  - "Saul Chaplin", 1971 (Box 43)
  - "Dorothy Fields", undated (Box 43)
  - "Burton Lane", 1972 (Box 43)
  - Bock/Harnick", undated (Box 43)
  - Notes, 1972 (Box 43)
  - "Short Takes", 1971, undated (Box 43)
  - Notes, 1972 (Box 43)
  - "Irving Caesar", 1971 (Box 43)
  - "Joshua Logan", 1972 (Box 43)
  - John Barrymore, program, 1982 (Box 43)
  - "Reminiscences of Sol Lesser," Oral Research Office, Columbia University 1970, typescript. (Box 43)
  - Irving Berlin's "This is the Army," rough draft, 2000 (Box 43)
  - The Dramatists Guild Quarterly Spring and Summer issues, 1967 (Box 43)
  - Issues of ASCAP Today, 1969-1971; 2 (Box 43)
  - "Loesser", undated (Box 43)
  - "Lee Adams", 1971 (Box 43)
- October 2002 Acquisition, 1936-1998; 29; 0.42; (1 box)
  - List of theater production programs, undated (Box 44)
  - Theater production programs, primarily from New York and Connecticut theaters, 1936-1998; 60 (Box 44)
- November 2002 Acquisition, 1971-1975; 30; 0.21; (1 box)
  Corespondence, typescripts and clipping.
  - Lichtenstein, Roy, letter to Barbara Wilk, 1971 June 7 (Box 45)
  - Wodehouse, P. G., letters to Max Wilk, 1971-1975 (Box 45)
  - Wodehouse, P. G., untitled typescript on Jerome Kern, undated (Box 45)
  - Clipping of the New Yorker profile of P. G. Wodehouse by Herbert Warren Wind, 1971 (Box 45)
  - Untitled typescript reminiscence of London by Max Wilk, undated (Box 45)
- November 2002 Acquisition, 1947-2000; 31; 0.42; (1 box)
  American film history research material, including typed transcripts of interviews with screenwriters, producers, directors, and others.
  - Content box listing (Box 46)
  - Lewis, Al, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Marx, Sam (photocopy), transcript from an interview: January 25, 1972, undated (Box 46)
  - Weingarten, Lawrence, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Buchman, Sidney, 1973 February 10 (Box 46)
  - Viertel, Peter, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Bloom, Harold Jack, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Goodrich, Frances and Albert Hacket, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Collier, John, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Levy, Benn W., 1972 October 19 (Box 46)
  - Wilder, Billy, 1972 (Box 46)
  - Chodorov, Edward, 1973 (Box 46)
  - Johnson, Nunnally (photocopy), undated (Box 46)
  - Stewart, Donald Ogden, [1970?] (Box 46)
  - The Screenwriter, 1947 June (Box 46)
  - Hunter, Evan, 2000 May 3 (Box 46)
  - Hartman, Ed, 1977, 2000 (Box 46)
  - Miscellaneous, 1990, undated (Box 46)
- January 2003 Acquisition, 1979-1981; 32; 2; (2 boxes)
  Taped interviews with agent Audrey Wood regarding writers she represented including Carson McCullers, Truman Capote, Tennessee Williams and others, for Represented by Audrey Wood.